<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: projects | Tushar's Blog]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.tusharsaxena.com/blog/categories/projects/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.tusharsaxena.com/"/>
  <updated>2013-04-03T23:37:22-04:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.tusharsaxena.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Tushar Saxena]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[pow environment variable trouble]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.tusharsaxena.com/blog/2013/02/15/pow-environment-variable-trouble/"/>
    <updated>2013-02-15T01:57:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.tusharsaxena.com/blog/2013/02/15/pow-environment-variable-trouble</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I was caught up in excitement upon discovering <a href="http://pow.cx">pow</a>. After setting it up, and testing it out on the project I'm working on now, I encountered a problem. My app is setup to send email using Gmail thru SMTP configured in a Rails environment config, and the email is sent using ActionMailer.</p>

<p>The config looks like this
```</p>

<pre><code>address: "smtp.gmail.com",
port: 587,
user_name: ENV["GMAIL_USERNAME"],
password: ENV["GMAIL_PASSWORD"],
authentication: :login
</code></pre>

<p>```</p>

<p>  The emails were arriving when I tested the app by running <code>rails server</code> but on the local pow server, authentication errors were the norm. Clearly the environment variables weren't being set. So I googled pow's documentation for how to setup environment variables, ending up on <a href="http://pow.cx/manual.html#section_2.2">this page</a>. While reading through the linked section, I missed something critical.</p>

<p>  "Pow attempts to execute two scripts — first .powrc, then .powenv — <strong>in the application's root</strong>. Any environment variables exported from these scripts are passed along to Rack."</p>

<p>  So I idiotically set about creating a .powrc file in my user/bin directory. Obviously this did not work, but I wasted an hour or so tweaking random settings trying to get this to work. Then I re-read the page, set about to fix the problem, which I did as follows.</p>

<ol>
<li>Run <code>touch .powrc</code> in my project's root.</li>
<li>Edit .powrc and add the environment variables as follows:
<code>
export GMAIL_USERNAME=username
export GMAIL_PASSWORD="my password"
</code></li>
<li>Restart pow's worker for the app by running
<code>touch tmp/restart.txt</code></li>
</ol>


<p>  And that worked!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
